ALISHA UPTON

York, PA 17402

Email: aliau2050@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/alishaupton</u> **CodePen:** <u>codepen.io/cyan-byte</u>

Design Portfolio: au-portfolio.vercel.app/

SUMMARY

An emerging Front-end Developer and UX/UI Designer. Proactive and resourceful learner, with 6+ years of experience in retail warehouse inventory control resolution.

Collaborator and team player with some leadership experience. Proficient with JavaScript, CSS, and HTML. Regarded for attention to detail, respect for design principles, work ethic, integrity, and a commitment to excellence.

Languages: English, some Spanish, some American Sign Language (ASL)

TECHNICAL TOOLBOX

- Front End Web Development
- Typesetting
- Color Theory
- Design Principles
- Figma
- Wireframing
- UX & UI Design
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Problem-Solving
- MongoDB
- GitHub
- JavaScript, CSS, HTML
- React, Redux, Node.js, JSX

EDUCATION

Per Scholas, Baltimore, MD October 2023

Software Engineering Intensive

Academy of Art University, San Francisco, CA Some Credits

Sept. 2020

Web Design and New Media

Art Institute of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA February 2015

Digital Graphical Design 1-year Program

WORK EXPERIENCE

Quadrant Resource, Redmond, WA (Remote) 3/2020 – 10/2020 *Web Data Analyst*

- Analyzed search queries from search engines and Al assistants, such as Google and Bing.
- Categorized user voice queries from A.I. assistants.
- Labeled user input data using proprietary software.
- Operated the backend of Siri and Alexa including analyzing audio queries

Rev.com, San Francisco, CA (Remote) 7/2019 – 3/2020 Closed Captioner & Transcriber

- Transcribed audio and video content using Rev's proprietary software.
- Researched industry jargon and proper nouns before transcribing.
- Self-edited/proofread, typed 60+ WPM.
- Listen well to audio and pay close attention to detail.

Joseph A. Bank Clothiers, Hampstead, MD 1/2011 – 6/2017 *Inventory Control Problem Solver*

- Managed 6 zones of 130,000+ units of inventory
- Created Excel spreadsheets to track vendor purchase orders and reconciliations.
- Pulled and packed orders for customers and retail stores.
- Processed damages from assigned warehouse zones, and collaborated with a 6-person cycle count team to count and scan inventory across two warehouses.